# Ryan Chen 陳俊綱

cell: 0966395847 • email: ryan26tw@yahoo.com

#### **OBJECTIVE**

To obtain a full-time position in Sr. Front-End Engineer.

#### **PROFILE**

A passionate and self-motivated Web Developer with 15+ years of professional experience in web development. A proactive learner and team player with experience in an agile and teamwork environment. Specialize in turning UI designs into clean, scalable and maintainable web sites and applications.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Software Engineer - FrontEnd, Gorilla Technology - Taipei City, Taiwan • Dec 2017 - Present

- Work on the front-end web applications development for the various company's products and projects.
- Discuss and design the technical specifications with the Product Manager to come up with the product UX flow to create great user experiences.
- Provide feedback and technical aspects with the Product Manager and UI team in the design meetings.
- Develop, maintain, test, build and deliver the high quality front-end code.

#### Front End Developer, ASUS - Taipei City, Taiwan • May 2017 - Nov 2017

- Responsible for building the ASUS ROG Forum site from scratch.
- Help identify and fix the bug for the company global official website.
- Develop and maintain the official websites and internal sites in the company.

## Sr. Software Engineer, Verizon - San Jose, CA USA • August 2014 - May 2017

- Work closely with Product Managers and UI/UX Designers to clarify product specs and functional flows.
- Provide insights and feedbacks on technical aspects when the new project begins.
- Participate in brainstorm sessions to gather input to apply changes for prototype iterations.
- Build high quality and top performance applications that work on various browsers and devices.

#### Web Developer (Contractor), Google - Mountain View, CA USA • May 2013 - May 2014

- Develop and maintain innovative and informative websites for the worldwide Google users.
- Fulfill several project requests and bug fixes simultaneously while meeting tight deadlines.
- Responsible for the creation of high quality, world class web content for desktop and mobile devices.
- Work with Marketing and Product Managers to receive feedbacks and requests of the projects.

## Staff Software Engineer, E\*TRADE - Menlo Park • CA USA, October 2011 - April 2013

- Responsible for building the UI of the web-based mobile application for tablets.
- Work with Product Manager and QA for the development and testing cycle of the application.
- Develop pixel precision pages to support different mobile platforms and browsers.
- Responsible for debugging cross-browser and cross-platform issues on touch screen devices.

## Web Developer, QuinStreet - Foster City, CA USA • August 2006 - August 2011

- Collaborate with Web Producers to innovate and create websites to meet the company's business goals.
- Develop and test the code to improve sites overall performance, effectiveness and usability.
- Implement components for new features to improve content relevance and SEO best practices.
- Responsible for both client-side and server-side development, as well as the MySQL database designs.

# **QUALIFICATIONS**

- Proficient in front-end languages HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Solid knowledge of JavaScript frameworks in React, Vue.js and AngularJS.
- Strong knowledge of Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Material-UI, Bootstrap, Sass and Responsive Web Design.
- Working knowledge in Git version control, Source Tree, webpack, Postman and Chrome developer tool.
- Experience in Node.js, Express, Jenkins build and Jest JavaScript Testing Framework.
- Solid understanding of MySQL database and NoSQL database with MongoDB.
- Experience in programming with Python, PHP and Java. Familiar with linux commands.
- Understanding of HTTP, SEO, accessibility, cross-platform and cross-browser compatibility.

# **SKILLS**

Software: Proficient in operating Mac OS and Microsoft Windows / Office. Language: Fluency in Chinese and English. Basic knowledge in Japanese.

Certificate: Japanese-Language Proficiency Test (JLPT) N4 certified, January 2010.

Personality: Excellent communication skills. Good interpersonal skills and strong attention to details.

# **PORTFOLIO**

RyanChenWeb - <a href="https://ryanchenweb.netlify.app">https://ryanchenweb.netlify.app</a>
LinkedIn - <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryan-chen-web">https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryan-chen-web</a>

# **EDUCATION**

San Jose State University, San Jose, CA USA • B.S. in Electrical Engineering • December 2004